<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Albin Fontaine on Albin Fontaine</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Albin Fontaine on Albin Fontaine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of a vector-borne incubation period distribution: a Star Wars story</title>
      <link>/post/estimation-of-a-vector-borne-incubation-period-distribution-a-star-wars-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/estimation-of-a-vector-borne-incubation-period-distribution-a-star-wars-story/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;background&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;a-mysterious-disease-has-emerged-on-planet-naboo.-both-infected-humans-and-other-extra-terrestrial-life-forms-experience-fever-severe-headaches-skin-rash-and-mild-bleeding-symptoms.-the-first-order-has-sent-health-experts-in-the-area.-they-identified-the-causing-agent-as-being-a-vector-borne-virus-transmitted-by-an-autochthonous-mosquito-species.-estimating-the-virus-incubation-period-in-vertebrate-hosts-would-help-to-determine-the-duration-of-the-containment-measure-to-control-the-outbreak.&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A mysterious disease has emerged on planet Naboo. Both infected humans and other extra-terrestrial life forms experience fever, severe headaches, skin rash and mild bleeding symptoms. The FIRST ORDER has sent health experts in the area. They identified the causing agent as being a vector-borne virus transmitted by an autochthonous mosquito species. Estimating the virus incubation period in vertebrate hosts would help to determine the duration of the containment measure to control the outbreak.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will see here how to estimate an incubation period distribution in veterbrate hosts for a vector-borne pathogen. Vector-borne pathogens have a transmission cycle that involve invertebrate hosts (called the vector, i.e. mosquitoes, ticks, phlebotomes…) and vertebrate hosts (i.e., human or here extra-terrestrial :). We will assume here that virus acquisition by the vertebrate host can only be due to an infectious mosquito bites. Incubation period (IP) is defined here as the time elapsed from virus acquisition to onset of symptoms in vertebrate host. We will only focus on symptomatic infection here. Estimating the duration of IP in vertebrate hosts is not straightforward for vector-borne pathogens because date of infection through the bite of an infectious vector cannot usually be determined. People are usually bitten all the time by insects and they cannot trace back an infectious bite in time. We will exploit here declared travel and symptom dates of travelers entering or leaving areas with ongoing virus transmission with interval-censored time to event (survival) analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This code was used for the paper “Variability of Zika Virus Incubation Period in Humans” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30397624&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30397624&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;load-packages&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Load packages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need these packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(msm)
library(survival)
library(plyr)
library(ggplot2)
library(lubridate)
library(interval)
library(icenReg)
#library(survminer) #Survminer is a nice package to visualize non-parametric survival curves. But I could&amp;#39;nt make it work on interval censored data.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;generate-data&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Generate data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generate a data.frame here. The first column of the data.frame is patient IDs, the second column indicates if they belong to the human race (Human=yes or no), the third column (Arrival) indicates the declared date of arrival in Naboo, the planet with active virus transmission. The last column indicates the duration of the stay in Naboo. All patients are travelers that visited the planet for a short period. There is no reported active virus transmission elsewhere in the galaxies. I generate a declared symptom onset date based on the date of arrival + a random number in the interval [1 ; Length_of_stay-1] + a incubation period drawn from a truncated (null or negative values not allowed) normal distribution, i.e. N(mean, SD=4). The mean for each patient category is indicated below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;set.seed(12)

Mean_ip_human &amp;lt;- 6 # Mean incubation period in human
Mean_ip_alien &amp;lt;- 12 # Mean incubation period in alien

data &amp;lt;- data.frame(ID=seq(1,194,1),
                      Name=c(paste(&amp;quot;Wookie&amp;quot;,1:14, sep=&amp;quot;_&amp;quot;),paste(&amp;quot;Ewok&amp;quot;,1:50, sep=&amp;quot;_&amp;quot;), paste(&amp;quot;Stormtrooper&amp;quot;,1:70, sep=&amp;quot;_&amp;quot;), paste(&amp;quot;Snowtrooper&amp;quot;,1:60,sep=&amp;quot;_&amp;quot;)),
                      Human=c(rep(&amp;quot;no&amp;quot;,64), rep(&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot;,70+60)) ,
                      Arrival=sample(seq(as.Date(&amp;quot;2016/01/01&amp;quot;), as.Date(&amp;quot;2018/01/01&amp;quot;), by=&amp;quot;day&amp;quot;), 194) ,
                      Length_of_stay_declared_days= round(rtnorm(194, mean = 15, sd = 4, lower=1)))

data&amp;lt;- ddply(data, .(ID), mutate,
                  Symptoms= if(Human==&amp;quot;no&amp;quot;) {Arrival + sample(x = 1:(Length_of_stay_declared_days-1), 1) + round(rtnorm(1, mean = Mean_ip_alien, sd = 5, lower=1))}else{Arrival + sample(x = 1:(Length_of_stay_declared_days-1), 1) + round(rtnorm(1, mean = Mean_ip_human, sd = 5, lower=1))})&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the lubridate package to convert dates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;data$Arrival &amp;lt;- ymd(as.character(data$Arrival)) #lubridate
data$Symptoms &amp;lt;- ymd(as.character(data$Symptoms )) #lubridate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets denote A for the date of Arrival in the zone of transmission (planet Naboo), D for date of Departure from planet Naboo and S for the date of Symptom declaration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to these terms we can calculate the following parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration of the stay in Naboo (Time_A_D)= D - A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration from departure from Naboo and symptom onset (Time_D_S) = S - D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duration from arrival in Naboo and symptom onsets (Time_A_S) = S - A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also use the lubridate package to calculate the day of departure from the day of arrival and the period of stay in the zone of active transmission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;data &amp;lt;- ddply(data, .(ID), mutate,
              Departure= Arrival + Length_of_stay_declared_days,
              Time_D_S= interval(Departure, Symptoms) %/% days(),
              Time_A_D= interval(Arrival,Departure ) %/% days(),
              Time_A_S= Time_A_D+Time_D_S)

data &amp;lt;- arrange(data, desc(Time_A_D))
data$ID &amp;lt;- factor(data$ID, levels=data$ID )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can represent the travel data graphically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;p &amp;lt;- ggplot(data=data)
p &amp;lt;- p + geom_vline(xintercept = 0, color = &amp;quot;black&amp;quot;, size=1 )
p &amp;lt;- p + geom_segment(aes(x = -Time_A_S , y = factor(ID), xend = -Time_D_S, yend = factor(ID), color=Human))
p &amp;lt;- p + geom_point(aes(x = -Time_A_S, y = factor(ID)), size = 2, color = &amp;quot;orange&amp;quot;)
p &amp;lt;- p + geom_point(aes(x = -Time_D_S, y = factor(ID)), size = 2, color = &amp;quot;forestgreen&amp;quot;)
p &amp;lt;- p + theme_bw(base_size = 20)
p &amp;lt;- p + theme(panel.grid.minor = element_blank(), panel.grid.major = element_blank(), axis.text.y=element_blank(), axis.ticks.y=element_blank())
#p &amp;lt;- p + facet_wrap(~Human, scales = &amp;quot;free_y&amp;quot;, nrow=2)
p &amp;lt;- p + ggtitle(&amp;quot;&amp;quot;) + ylab(&amp;quot;Individuals&amp;quot;)
p &amp;lt;- p + scale_color_manual(values = c(&amp;quot;dodgerblue3&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;deeppink2&amp;quot;))
p &amp;lt;- p + scale_x_continuous(name=&amp;quot;Time (days)&amp;quot;, limits=c(-100,30), breaks=seq(-100,30,10))
p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-12-15-estimation-of-a-vector-borne-incubation-period-distribution-a-star-wars-story_files/figure-html/4-1.png&#34; width=&#34;576&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vertical black line represents the onset of symptoms. Travel data from human and not human patients are represented with colored horizontal lines. The arrival and departure from the area with ongoing virus transmission is represented with an orange and green dot, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exposure interval is delineated by the arrival date and the departure date for travelers that experienced symptoms after returning from travel, whereas the period separating the arrival date and the symptom onset date delineated the exposure interval in travelers experiencing illness during the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can thus define the exposure interval with 2 different manners. Concerning patients experiencing symptoms after departure from endemic zone: exposure interval = Time_A_D Concerning patients experiencing symptoms during the trip: exposure interval = Time_A_S&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am creating the interval censored data (Surv object) conditionally:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;data$left &amp;lt;- NA
data$right &amp;lt;- data$Time_A_S

for(i in 1:nrow(data)) {
if(data[i,&amp;quot;Time_D_S&amp;quot;] &amp;lt; 0) {data[i,&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;] &amp;lt;- 0}else{data[i,&amp;quot;left&amp;quot;] &amp;lt;- data[i,&amp;quot;Time_D_S&amp;quot;]}
}

temp &amp;lt;- with(data, Surv(left,right,type=&amp;quot;interval2&amp;quot;))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;non-parametric-model&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Non-parametric model&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first use non-parametric time to event model, which are the most robust (no bias related to mispecification of the hazard distribution). I am using here the icfit function from the &lt;em&gt;interval&lt;/em&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;fit&amp;lt;-icfit(temp~Human, data=data, conf.int=T )
#summary(fit)

#Cumulative distribution function
plot(fit, conf.int = F, COL = c(&amp;quot;deeppink2&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;dodgerblue3&amp;quot;))
abline(h=0.5, col=&amp;quot;gold3&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-12-15-estimation-of-a-vector-borne-incubation-period-distribution-a-star-wars-story_files/figure-html/6-1.png&#34; width=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary(fit) provides non-parametric maximum likelihood estimates (NPMLEs) of the IP distribution (generalization of the Kaplan-Meier estimate) with a modified bootstrap confidence interval (CI) method. Estimates are calculated over a set of time intervals called Turnbull intervals, which represent the innermost intervals over a group of individuals in which NPMLE can change. Median survival estimates correspond to the time where the survival probability reaches 0.5 (gold horizontal line).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The median IP occured during the interval [6;7] for humans and [11;12] for extra-terrestrials. That correspond to mean values that we have setted up previously :smiley:.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can apply some statistical tests (non-parametric log-rank tests) implemented in the interval package:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;#logrank: Sun&amp;#39;s scores
test&amp;lt;-ictest(temp~Human, data=data)
test

#logrank: Finkelstein&amp;#39;s scores
test&amp;lt;-ictest(temp~Human, data=data, scores=&amp;quot;logrank2&amp;quot;)
test

#Wilcoxon-type tests
test&amp;lt;-ictest(temp~Human, data=data, scores=&amp;quot;wmw&amp;quot;)
test

#Wilcoxon-type tests, exact Monte Carlo
test&amp;lt;-ictest(temp~Human, data=data, scores=&amp;quot;wmw&amp;quot;, exact=T)
test&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patient category is significantly impacting the duration of virus incubation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;parametric-model-accelerated-failure-time-regression-model-aft&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Parametric model (accelerated failure-time regression model (AFT))&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now are going to model the incubation period distribution using parametric models (accelerated failure-time regression models (AFT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fully parametric models provide more efficient inference and quantification of uncertainty of time to event estimates (smoother probability distribution with restricted confidence intervals) at the cost of requiring a correct assumption of the baseline distribution family. The use of fully parametric models is also convenient because they link a time post virus exposure to a probability of symptom onset through an equation with estimated parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first have to determine the baseline function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;diag_baseline(temp ~ 1,
              model = &amp;quot;ph&amp;quot;,
              data = data,
              dists = c(&amp;quot;exponential&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;weibull&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;loglogistic&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;gamma&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;lnorm&amp;quot;),
              lgdLocation = &amp;quot;topright&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-12-15-estimation-of-a-vector-borne-incubation-period-distribution-a-star-wars-story_files/figure-html/8-1.png&#34; width=&#34;768&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose the loglogistic baseline distribution. We will now use the &lt;em&gt;icenReg&lt;/em&gt; package (&lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/icenReg/vignettes/icenReg.pdf&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/icenReg/vignettes/icenReg.pdf&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;fit_loglogistic &amp;lt;- ic_par(temp ~ Human, data = data, model = &amp;quot;aft&amp;quot;, dist = &amp;quot;loglogistic&amp;quot;)
summary(fit_loglogistic)

newdata&amp;lt;-data.frame(Human=levels(data$Human))
rownames(newdata) &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;Not human&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Human&amp;quot;)

survCIs(fit_loglogistic, p=0.5, newdata = newdata) #Median estimates
survCIs(fit_loglogistic, p=0.95, newdata = newdata) #95th centiles estimates

plot(fit_loglogistic, newdata = newdata, fun = &amp;quot;cdf&amp;quot;)
abline(h=0.5, col=&amp;quot;gold3&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-12-15-estimation-of-a-vector-borne-incubation-period-distribution-a-star-wars-story_files/figure-html/9-1.png&#34; width=&#34;1152&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot displays parametric estimates of virus incubation period probabilities over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The median estimates are 11.2 days and 6.4 days for aliens and human, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;bayesian-accelerated-failure-time-regression-model-aft&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bayesian accelerated failure-time regression model (AFT):&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The icenReg R package dedicated to interval censored data offers the opportunity to extend fully parametric models to the Bayesian framework. In this case, Bayesian inference is used to estimate the log-logistic baseline distribution parameters (shape and scale) instead of maximum likelihood estimation (MLE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will use flat priors here. You can refer to &lt;em&gt;icenReg&lt;/em&gt; package documentation if you want to use priors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bayes_fit &amp;lt;- ic_bayes(temp ~ Human,
                      data = data,
                      model = &amp;quot;aft&amp;quot;, dist = &amp;quot;loglogistic&amp;quot;,
                      controls = bayesControls(samples = 100000, chains = 4, useMLE_start = TRUE,
                                               burnIn = 1000))

(CI &amp;lt;- survCIs(bayes_fit, p=0.5, newdata = newdata))
(CI2 &amp;lt;- survCIs(bayes_fit, p=0.95, newdata = newdata))

plot(bayes_fit, newdata = newdata, fun = &amp;quot;cdf&amp;quot;)
abline(h=0.5, col=&amp;quot;gold3&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-12-15-estimation-of-a-vector-borne-incubation-period-distribution-a-star-wars-story_files/figure-html/10-1.png&#34; width=&#34;1152&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bayesian median estimates are 11.12 days and 6.39 days for aliens and human, respectively, it is not very different from AFT estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Blogdown</title>
      <link>/post/hello-r-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hello-r-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A major turnover in my young scientist career was to learn how to code in the R environment. R brought my science abilities to a next level and allowed me to be transversal: to deal with huge data sets, perform simple and hard-core statistic tests, visualize complex data, create maps, &amp;hellip; without knowing anything else than applying a very well documented R package or R tutorial. Hey! &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt; also allows me to create a website so easily thanks to the R Blogdown (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&lt;/a&gt;) package and Hugo with academic theme (&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&lt;/a&gt;) without any background. I am infinitely grateful to all members of the R community that have helped R to become what it is today through numerous open-source packages, tutorials or blogs. Through my “behind the paper tutorials”, I aim to bring my modest contribution by sharing some of my code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation of an arbovirus incubation period distribution based on travellers data: A Star Wars example</title>
      <link>/tutorial/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tutorial/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We will see here how to estimate an incubation period distribution in humans for a vector-borne pathogen. Incubation period (IP) is defined as the time elapsed from virus acquisition to onset of symptoms in humans. Estimating the duration of IP in humans is not straightforward for vector-borne diseases because date of infection through the bite of an infectious vector cannot usually be determined. We will exploit here declared travel and symptom dates of travelers entering or leaving areas with ongoing virus transmission.
This code was used for the paper &amp;ldquo;Variability of Zika Virus Incubation Period in Humans&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30397624&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30397624&lt;/a&gt;). For data confidentiality purpose, we are going to use here a fake dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;load-packages&#34;&gt;Load packages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r,&#34;&gt;library(survival)
library(plyr)
library(ggplot2)
library(lubridate)
library(interval)
library(icenReg)
library(survminer)

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;load-data-set&#34;&gt;Load data set&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r,&#34;&gt;
data &amp;lt;- read.table(file = &amp;quot;Data_IP_fake.txt&amp;quot;, h=T)
head(data)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved reference genome of Aedes aegypti informs arbovirus vector control</title>
      <link>/publication/nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variability of Zika virus incubation period in humans</title>
      <link>/publication/zikv_incubation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/zikv_incubation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epidemiological significance of dengue virus genetic variation in mosquito infection dynamics</title>
      <link>/publication/plospath_epidemiological_sign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/plospath_epidemiological_sign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extensive Genetic Differentiation between Homomorphic Sex Chromosomes in the Mosquito Vector, Aedes aegypti</title>
      <link>/publication/gbe_extensive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/gbe_extensive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excretion of dengue virus RNA by Aedes aegypti allows non-destructive monitoring of viral dissemination in individual mosquitoes</title>
      <link>/publication/excretion_denv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/excretion_denv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>/project/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Project</title>
      <link>/project/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic mapping of specific interactions between Aedes aegypti mosquitoes and dengue viruses</title>
      <link>/publication/genetic_mapping_plosgen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/genetic_mapping_plosgen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implication of haematophagous arthropod salivary proteins in host-vector interactions</title>
      <link>/publication/pv_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/pv_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/example-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/slides/example-slides/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
